{
    "question": "380)  Who has been appointed as the new Foreign Secretary of India",
    "answer": " \nHarsh Vardhan Shringla \n"
}{
    "question": "382)  Assassination of Mahatma Gandhi took place in which year",
    "answer": " \n1948 \n"
}{
    "question": "383)  What is the title of the book recently written by Mukhtar Abbas \nNaqvi, Union Minister of Minority Affairs",
    "answer": " Balwa  (uprising) \nDownload Gyanm App from Play Store  147 \n (Stay Updated on Govt Jobs: WhatsApp 'Hello' to 9117-343434) \n"
}{
    "question": "384)  American Dirt is a popular novel released in January 2020 Who \nis its author",
    "answer": " Jeanine Cummins \n"
}{
    "question": "385)  Which Ministry launched online portal \u2018GATI\u2019 for monitoring \nmajor projects of the National Highways Authority of India \n(NHAI)",
    "answer": " Union Road Transport Ministry \n"
}{
    "question": "386)  Which stat government launched the Shiv Bhojan Scheme to \nprovide  a  regular  meal  in  just  Rs  10  to  commoners",
    "answer": " \nMaharashtra \n"
}{
    "question": "387)  The 62nd annual Grammy Awards were presented at the Staples \nCenter  in  Los  Angeles  They  recognize  the  outstanding \nexcellence in which field",
    "answer": " Music \n"
}{
    "question": "388)  Name the artist who created history by sweeping all the four top \nGrammy Awards 2020",
    "answer": " Billie Eilish (USA) \n"
}{
    "question": "389)  According  to  the  recent  data  released  by  the  Agriculture \nMinistry, which state topped in the production of vegetables",
    "answer": " \nWest Bengal  \n"
}{
    "question": "390)  State of ____________ produced the largest quantity of fruits in \n2018-19",
    "answer": " Andhra Pradesh \n"
}{
    "question": "391)  The central govt signed a peace accord on January 27 with the \ninsurgent tribal groups of which state",
    "answer": " Assam \n"
}{
    "question": "392)  This accord was sign with which tribal groups",
    "answer": " Bodos \n"
}{
    "question": "393)  Bodos occupy which part of Assam",
    "answer": " Western Assam, north of \nBrahmaputra \n"
}{
    "question": "394)  The Coronavirus wreaked havoc in China Which Chinese city \nsuffered the most",
    "answer": " Wuhan \n"
}{
    "question": "395)  The Coronovirus generally causes which kind of illness",
    "answer": " Acute \nrespiratory syndromes \n"
}{
    "question": "396)  The Supreme Court granted how much reservation to persons \nwith disabilities in all public sector jobs",
    "answer": " 3% \n"
}{
    "question": "397)  Name the veteran American basketball player who was killed in \na helicopter crash in California, USA",
    "answer": " Kobe Bryant  \n"
}{
    "question": "398)  The  World  Bank  approved  a  loan  of  $210  million  for \nAgribusiness and Rural Transformation Project of which state",
    "answer": " \nMaharashtra \n"
}{
    "question": "399)  Out of George Fernandes, Sushma Swaraj, Arun Jaitley and \nManohar Parrikar, whose name does not figure in this year's \nPadma Vibhushan Awards",
    "answer": " Manohar Parikar \n"
}{
    "question": "400)  Name the only sports person who has been considered for award \nof Padma Vibhushan this year",
    "answer": " MC Mary Kom \nDownload Gyanm App from Play Store  148 \n (Stay Updated on Govt Jobs: WhatsApp 'Hello' to 9117-343434) \n"
}{
    "question": "401)  Shuttler  PV  Sindhu  andindustrialist  Anand  Mahindra  were \nselected for which Padma award this year",
    "answer": " Padma Bhushan \n"
}{
    "question": "402)  World Leprosy Day is observed on which date",
    "answer": " Last Sunday of \nJanuary \n"
}{
    "question": "403)  The Leprosy disease affects which parts of the body",
    "answer": " Skin and \nnerves  \n"
}{
    "question": "404)  At which Indian airport a special all women taxi service named \n'Women  with  wheels'  was  launched  recently",
    "answer": "  Indira  Gandhi \nInternational Airport, New Delhi \n"
}{
    "question": "405)  President of which country was the Chief Guest at the 71st \nRepublic Day Parade ceremony at Rajpath, New Delhi",
    "answer": " Brazil \n"
}{
    "question": "406)  What is the name of the first ever humanoid unveiled recently \nby the ISRO",
    "answer": " Vyomitra \n"
}{
    "question": "407)  The DRDO successfully test-fired its K-4 nuclear capable missile \nrecently from which launch pad",
    "answer": " Submarine \n"
}{
    "question": "408)  Which is the first telecom company to provide UPI-powered \npayments service for its subscribers",
    "answer": " Reliance Jio \n"
}{
    "question": "409)  What is the full form of UPI",
    "answer": " Unified Payments Interface  \n"
}{
    "question": "411)  What is the name of the debit / credit card launched by NPCI",
    "answer": " \nRuPay \n"
}{
    "question": "412)  Which day is observed on January 25 every year to spread \nawareness about the necessity of voting and to encourage young \ngeneration towards the voting rights",
    "answer": " National Voters Day \n"
}{
    "question": "413)  Why January 25 has been selected to celebrate National Voters \nDay",
    "answer": " The Election Commission of India came into existence on \nthis day in 1950 \n"
}{
    "question": "414)  Headquarters of Election Commission of India in New Delhi are \nknown by which name",
    "answer": " NirvachanSadan \n"
}{
    "question": "415)  What was India's rank in the recently released Global Talent \nCompetitive Index (GTCI) 2020",
    "answer": " 72nd \n"
}{
    "question": "417)  Celebration of International Day of Education is supported by \nwhich UN organization",
    "answer": " UNESCO \n"
}{
    "question": "418)  International  Day  of  Education  is  observed  on  which  date",
    "answer": " \nJanuary 24 \n"
}{
    "question": "419)  India  observes  National  Education  Day  on  which  date",
    "answer": " \nDownload Gyanm App from Play Store  149 \n (Stay Updated on Govt Jobs: WhatsApp 'Hello' to 9117-343434) \nNovember 11 \n"
}{
    "question": "421)  India  celebrates  National  Girl  Child  Day  on  which  date",
    "answer": " \nJanuary 24 \n"
}{
    "question": "422)  Which  organization  launched  a  blockchain-technology  based \npayment  system  \u2018Vajra  Platform\u2019",
    "answer": "  National  Payments \nCorporation of India (NPCI) \n"
}{
    "question": "423)  Customers of which bank will now be able to withdraw cash \nfrom ATMs without their debit cards",
    "answer": " ICICI Bank \n"
}{
    "question": "427)  Which  NGO  compiles  the  Corruption  Perception  Index",
    "answer": " \nTransparency International \n"
}{
    "question": "428)  Which two countries shared equal marks to secure top position \nin the Corruption Perception Index",
    "answer": " New Zeeland and Denmark \n"
}{
    "question": "429)  Airpocalypse, a study of  air pollution level in 287 Indian cities \ndeclared which 2 coal mining cities as the most polluted",
    "answer": " Jharia \nand Dhanbad \n"
}{
    "question": "430)  Jharia and Dhanbad are located in which state",
    "answer": " Jharkhand  \n"
}{
    "question": "431)  Crystal Awards are associated with which field",
    "answer": " Social Work by \nexceptional artist  \n"
}{
    "question": "432)  Which organization is associated with Crystal Awards",
    "answer": " World \nEconomic Forum \n"
}{
    "question": "435)  What is the full form of the acronym PRAGATI",
    "answer": " Pro-Active \nGovernance and Timely Implementation \n"
}{
    "question": "436)  EkateriniSakellaropoulou has been elected as the first woman \nDownload Gyanm App from Play Store  150 \n (Stay Updated on Govt Jobs: WhatsApp 'Hello' to 9117-343434) \nPresident of which country",
    "answer": " Greece \n"
}{
    "question": "437)  In  which  metro  city  shops  and  business  establishments  like \nmultiplexes and malls have been allowed to remain open 24x7",
    "answer": " \nMumbai \n"
}{
    "question": "439)  Which state won the Champions trophy in the 3rd Khelo India \nYouth Games",
    "answer": " Maharashtra \n"
}{
    "question": "441)  Which organization compiles the Democracy Index",
    "answer": " Economist \nIntelligence Unit,  London \n"
}{
    "question": "442)  Which country topped the Democracy Index 2019",
    "answer": " Norway \n"
}{
    "question": "443)  Arjun Munda elected as the President of Archery Association of \nIndia Who is he",
    "answer": " Union Minister for Tribal Affairs \n"
}{
    "question": "444)  With  which  neighbouring  country  India  opened  an  ICP  at \nBiratnagar",
    "answer": " Nepal  \n"
}{
    "question": "445)  What is the full form of ICP",
    "answer": " Integrated Check Post \n"
}{
    "question": "446)  Which is the Indian counterpart city for the Biratnagar ICP",
    "answer": " \nJogbani, Bihar \n"
}{
    "question": "447)  India  secured  which  rank  on  the  annual  Carbon  Disclosure \nProject (CDP) 2019 report",
    "answer": " 5th  \n"
}{
    "question": "448)  Carbon  Disclosure  Project  (CDP)  2019  report  placed  which \ncountry at the top spot",
    "answer": " USA \n"
}{
    "question": "449)  Which senior BJP leader has been elected as the 11th President \nof the party",
    "answer": " Jagat Prakash Nadda \n"
}{
    "question": "450)  Sanjiv Chadha has been appointed as the MD & CEO of which \nBank",
    "answer": " Bank of Baroda  \n"
}{
    "question": "451)  Which  international  organization  lowered  India\u2019s  economic \ngrowth forecast to 4o8 percent for 2019-20, from 6o1 percent \nprojected in October",
    "answer": " International Monetary Fund  \n"
}{
    "question": "452)  The World Economic Outlook report is brought out by which \nInternational Body",
    "answer": "   International Monetary Fund \n"
}{
    "question": "453)  Which global NGO held its annual meeting at Davos attracting \nsome  3,000  leading  business/political  leaders,  economists, \ncelebrities and journalists",
    "answer": " World Economic Forum \n"
}{
    "question": "454)  Davos is located in which country",
    "answer": " Switzerland  \n"
}{
    "question": "455)  Who is the founder chairman of WEF",
    "answer": " Klaus Schwab \n"
}{
    "question": "456)  The  World  Economic  Forum  is  based  at  which  city  in \nDownload Gyanm App from Play Store  151 \n (Stay Updated on Govt Jobs: WhatsApp 'Hello' to 9117-343434) \nSwitzerland",
    "answer": " Geneva \n"
}{
    "question": "457)  At  which  place  the  Indian  Air  Force  has  inducted  its  first \nsquadron  of  Sukhoi-30 MKI  aircraft  carrying the  supersonic \nBrahMos missiles",
    "answer": " Thanjavur, Tamil Nadu \n"
}{
    "question": "458)  Which  country  has  shared  technology  with  India  to  make \nSukhoi-30 MKI fighter jets in India",
    "answer": " Russia \n"
}{
    "question": "462)  The  Social  Mobility  Index  is  topped  by  which  country",
    "answer": " \nDenmark \n"
}{
    "question": "463)  Which organization is responsible for bringing out the Social \nMobility Index",
    "answer": " World Economic Forum \n"
}{
    "question": "466)  What was the name of the joint exercise of  Indian Coast Guard \nand the Japan Coast Guard held recently",
    "answer": " Sahyog-Kaijin \n"
}{
    "question": "467)  The joint exercise Sahyog-Kaijin was held at which place",
    "answer": " Off \nthe Chennai coast \n"
}{
    "question": "468)   Mikhail  V  Mishustin  has  been  elected  by  the  Russian \nParliament as the country's new __________ ",
    "answer": "Prime Minister \n"
}{
    "question": "470)   What  is  the  full  form  of  IUCN",
    "answer": "    International  Union  for \nConservation of Nature \n"
}{
    "question": "471)  What are Orchids",
    "answer": "  Attractive flowering plants \n"
}{
    "question": "472)  What  is  meant  by  red  listing  of  species",
    "answer": "  It  is  listing  of \nthreatenedspecies that need conservation \n"
}{
    "question": "474)  The first edition of Krishi Manthan- the largest Food, Agri-\nbusiness and Rural Development Summit of Asia was held at \nDownload Gyanm App from Play Store  152 \n (Stay Updated on Govt Jobs: WhatsApp 'Hello' to 9117-343434) \nwhich place",
    "answer": " Ahmedabad  \n"
}{
    "question": "475)  VineshPhogat,  Anshu  Malik  are  the  top  ______  of  India",
    "answer": " \nWomen wrestler \n"
}{
    "question": "477)  Name the senior Indian Advocate who has been appointed as \nthe Queen's Counsel (QC) for the courts of England and Wales",
    "answer": " \nHarish Salve \n"
}{
    "question": "478)  Which neighbouring country of India suffered a setback in GDP \ngrowth, sinking down to 6o1%, lowest in 3 decades",
    "answer": " China \n"
}{
    "question": "479)  RobertAbela elected as the new Prime Minister of Malta Where \nis Malta",
    "answer": " A tiny island country in the Mediteranean Sea \n"
}{
    "question": "480)   Sir  Garfield  Sobers  Trophy  is  associated  with  outstanding \nperformance in which field",
    "answer": " Cricket \n"
}{
    "question": "481)   Who won the Sir Garfield Sobers Trophy for Best Cricketer of \nthe Year 2019, awarded by the ICC",
    "answer": " Ben Stokes, England \n"
}{
    "question": "483)  As per the agreement, the Bru-Reangtribals will now be settled \nin _______ state of India",
    "answer": " Tripura \n"
}{
    "question": "484)  ISRO\u2019s   high  power  communication  satellite  GSAT-30  was \nsuccessfully  launched  onboard  Ariane  5  rocket  from  which \nplace",
    "answer": " French Guiana \n"
}{
    "question": "485)  The GSAT-30 satellite will be used for improving services in \nwhich field",
    "answer": " Telecommunication and broadcasting  \n"
}{
    "question": "486)  The prestigious literary award 'SaraswatiSamman' is conferred \nfor outstanding contribution to literature in which language",
    "answer": " 22 \nlanguages listed in Schedule VIII of the Constitution of India \n"
}{
    "question": "487)  Who won the SaraswatiSamman for 2019",
    "answer": " VasdevMohi \n"
}{
    "question": "488)  VasdevMohi  won  the  SaraswatiSamman  for  which  book",
    "answer": " \nChequebook, a collection of short stories \n"
}{
    "question": "489)  What is the cash award component of the SaraswatiSamman",
    "answer": " \nRs15 lakh \n"
}{
    "question": "490)  VasdevMohi  is  a  prominent  writer  associated  with  which \nlanguage",
    "answer": " Sindhi \n"
}{
    "question": "491)  Which organization awards the SaraswatiSamman",
    "answer": " K K Birla \nFoundation, Delhi \n"
}{
    "question": "492)  Which Indian monument has been included by the Shanghai \nDownload Gyanm App from Play Store  153 \n (Stay Updated on Govt Jobs: WhatsApp 'Hello' to 9117-343434) \nCooperation Organization in its list of eight wonders",
    "answer": " Statue of \nUnity \n"
}{
    "question": "494)  Which day is celebrated on January 15 to mark the taking over \nof command of Indian Army by then Lt Gen K M Cariappa, the \nfirst  Indian  Commander-in-Chief,  from  the  British  General",
    "answer": " \nArmy Day \n"
}{
    "question": "496)  The 23rd National Youth Festival 2020 was held from 12-16 \nJanuary  It is associated with which great personality of India",
    "answer": " \nSwami Vivekananda \n"
}{
    "question": "497)  What is the linkage of Swami Vivekananda with the National \nYouth Day",
    "answer": " It is the birthday of Swami Vivekananda \n"
}{
    "question": "498)  The National Youth Day is celebrated on which date",
    "answer": " January \n12 \n"
}{
    "question": "499)  Who has been appointed as the new Director General of CRPF",
    "answer": " \nA P Maheshwari \n"
}{
    "question": "500)  What is the full form of CRPF",
    "answer": " Central Reserve Police Force  \n"
}{
    "question": "501)  Which  city  hosted  the  World  Future  Energy  Summit",
    "answer": "  Abu \nDhabi \n"
}{
    "question": "502)  Recently  we  read  about  'Raisina  Dialogue'  in  the  news \nheadlines What is it all about",
    "answer": " Itis theflagship global conference \nof India on geopolitics and geo-economicsissues \n"
}{
    "question": "503)  Which Indian city hosted the 'Raisina Dialogue' from January \n14 to 16",
    "answer": " New Delhi \n"
}{
    "question": "504)  Which is the popular festival of North India associated with end \nof  winter  solstice  and  beginning  of  summer  solstice",
    "answer": "  Makar \nSankranti  \n"
}{
    "question": "505)  The Makar Sankranti is celebrated popularly as Magh Bihu in \nwhich state",
    "answer": " Assam \n"
}{
    "question": "506)  People in Tamil Nadu celebrate occasion of Makar Sankranti as \n_________ festival",
    "answer": " Pongal \n"
}{
    "question": "507)  In  which  state  Makar  Sankranti  is  celebrated  as  Uttarayan \nfestival",
    "answer": " Gujarat \n"
}{
    "question": "508)  The Reserve Bank released a report titled \u201cNational Strategy \nfor Financial Inclusion: 2019-2024\u201d The report has identified \nDownload Gyanm App from Play Store  154 \n (Stay Updated on Govt Jobs: WhatsApp 'Hello' to 9117-343434) \nhow many pillars to achieve financial inclusion",
    "answer": " Six \n"
}{
    "question": "509)  The award for Best International Cricketer is given by BCCI in \nthe honour of which great cricketer",
    "answer": " Polly Umrigar \n"
}{
    "question": "510)  Who won this year's Polly Umrigar award for the best cricketer \nin Men's category",
    "answer": " JaspritBumrah \n"
}{
    "question": "513)  JaspritBumrah is specializes in which field of cricketer",
    "answer": " Right \narm fast bowling \n"
}{
    "question": "514)  The Polly Umrigar award for the best womencricketer -  has \nbeen won by",
    "answer": " Poonam Yadav \n"
}{
    "question": "515)  Poonam Yadav excels in which roll in the Indian Cricket Team",
    "answer": " \nLeg Spinner \n"
}{
    "question": "516)  What was the formal name of Swami Vivekananda",
    "answer": " Narendra \nNath Datta \n"
}{
    "question": "517)  What  is  the  name  of  the  popular  spiritual  and  educational \ninstitution  founded  by  Swami  Vivekananda",
    "answer": "  Ramkrishna \nMission \n"
}{
    "question": "518)  Henley  Passport  Index  2020  has  ranked Indian  passport  at \nwhich rank in the world",
    "answer": "  84th \n"
}{
    "question": "519)  Which  country  tops  the  Henley  Passport  Index  2020  for \nproviding visa-free access to 191 countries",
    "answer": " Japan \n"
}{
    "question": "521)  How many countries are there in European Union",
    "answer": " 28 \n"
}{
    "question": "523)  The RBI has amended the KYC norms allowing banks to use V-\nCIP What is its full form",
    "answer": " Video based Customer Identification \nProcess \n"
}{
    "question": "525)  India  celebrates  Rashtriya  Hindi  Divas  on  which  date",
    "answer": " \nSeptember 14 \n"
}{
    "question": "526)  Indian-origin  writer  JasbinderBilan  won  which  international \naward for her debut novel \u201cAsha and the Spirit Bird\u201d",
    "answer": "  UK \nDownload Gyanm App from Play Store  155 \n (Stay Updated on Govt Jobs: WhatsApp 'Hello' to 9117-343434) \nChildren's Book Award \n"
}{
    "question": "527)  The  Cabinet  Committee  on  Economic  Affairs  approved \n'Viability Gap Funding' worth Rs5559 crores to set up a natural \ngas pipeline grid in which part of the country",
    "answer": " North East  \n"
}{
    "question": "528)  Which  company  has  been  selected  to  set  up  a  natural  gas \npipeline grid in North East",
    "answer": " Indradhanush Gas Grid Limited \n"
}{
    "question": "529)  The 31st International Kite Festival was held in which city in \nthe second week of January",
    "answer": "  Ahmedabad, Gujarat \n"
}{
    "question": "530)  What was the name of the joint maritime exercise held by India \nand Oman navies",
    "answer": " \u2018Naseem Al Bahr\u2019 \n"
}{
    "question": "531)  Which country began a mass culling of up to 10,000 camels as \ntheir \u201cextremely large\u201d herds have been encroaching on rural \ncommunities",
    "answer": " Australia \n"
}{
    "question": "532)  Which bank has announced a 'residential builder finance with \nbuyer  guarantee'  (RBBG)  scheme,  to  improve  home  buyers' \nconfidence",
    "answer": " SBI \n"
}{
    "question": "533)  PravasiBharatiya Divas is observed on which date",
    "answer": " January 09 \n"
}{
    "question": "534)  PravasiBharatiya Divas celebrates the home coming of which \ngreat Indian leader on this day in 1915",
    "answer": " Mahatma Gandhi \n"
}{
    "question": "535)  NASA\u2019s TESS (Transiting Exoplanet Survey Satellite) recently \ndiscovered an earth-sized planet named TOI 700d What is its \nspecialty",
    "answer": " NASA expects this planet to be habitable  \n"
}{
    "question": "537)  Pedro  Sanchez  has  been  re-elected  as  the  Prime  Minister  of \nwhich country",
    "answer": " Spain \n"
}{
    "question": "538)  The 5th Ice Hockey Association of India (IHAI) National Ice \nHockey  Championship  -2020  was  held  in  which  place",
    "answer": "  Leh, \nLadakh \n"
}{
    "question": "539)  Which State / UTs won both, Men's and Women's title in the \nNational Ice Hockey Championship -2020",
    "answer": " Ladakh \n"
}{
    "question": "540)  Marine ecosystems are aquatic ecosystems whose waters possess \na high _______ content",
    "answer": " Salt \n"
}{
    "question": "541)  The  3rd  international  symposium  on  Marine  Ecosystems \nChallenges & Opportunities (MECOS-3) was hosted by which \ncity",
    "answer": " Kochi, Kerala \n"
}{
    "question": "542)  Which Indian paramilitary force has decided to observe 2020 as \nthe \u2018year of mobility\u2019 to focus on various welfare measures for \nDownload Gyanm App from Play Store  156 \n (Stay Updated on Govt Jobs: WhatsApp 'Hello' to 9117-343434) \nits troops",
    "answer": " CISF-Central Industrial Security Force \n"
}{
    "question": "543)  Which  country  recently  formally  approved  setting  up  of  its \nspecial Space Force",
    "answer": " USA \n"
}{
    "question": "544)   The first edition of Khelo India University Games is scheduled \nto be held at which university",
    "answer": " KIIT University in Bhubaneswar \n"
}{
    "question": "545)  Prof  Suresh  Chandra  Sharma  has  been  appointed  as  the \nchairman of which apex professional body",
    "answer": " National Medical \nCommission \n"
}{
    "question": "546)  C  K  Nayudu  Lifetime  Achievement  Award  is  given  for \nrecognizing  one's  outstanding  contribution  to  which  field",
    "answer": " \nCricket \n"
}{
    "question": "547)  Who  has  been  selected  for  the  C  K  Nayudu  Lifetime \nAchievement  Award  2019  in  Men's  category",
    "answer": " \nKrishnamachariSrikkanth \n"
}{
    "question": "548)  Who  has  been  selected  for  the  C  K  Nayudu  Lifetime \nAchievement Award 2019 in Women's category",
    "answer": " Anjum Chopra \n"
}{
    "question": "551)  Name  the  Indian  all-rounder  who  announced  his  retirement \nfrom all forms of Cricket",
    "answer": " Irfan Pathan \n"
}{
    "question": "552)  The Golden Globe Awards are associated with recognition of \nexcellence in which field",
    "answer": " Cinema and TV \n"
}{
    "question": "553)  Which picture won the Golden Globe for the best picture",
    "answer": " 1917 \n"
}{
    "question": "554)  Malavath Poorna,the 18-year-old mountaineer from Telangana \nrecently scaled Mt Vinson Massif It is the highest peak of \nwhich continent",
    "answer": " Antarctica \n"
}{
    "question": "555)  Recently KVIC open its first \u201cPatola\u201d silk processing plant at \nSurendranagar in Gujarat What is full form of KVIC",
    "answer": " Khadi \nand Village Industries Commission \n"
}{
    "question": "556)  \u201cPatola\u201d silk is famous for which product",
    "answer": " ExpensiveSilkSarees \n"
}{
    "question": "557)  Patola  sarees  from  which  place  enjoy  the  GI  tag  for  their \nexclusivity",
    "answer": "  Patan, Gujarat  \n"
}{
    "question": "558)  Name the star table Tennis player from UP who jumped nine \nplaces to become the world no 1 in the Under-21 men\u2019s singles \ncategory",
    "answer": " Manav Thakkar \n"
}{
    "question": "559)  What  was  the  name  of  the  person  who  developed  Braille \nDownload Gyanm App from Play Store  157 \n (Stay Updated on Govt Jobs: WhatsApp 'Hello' to 9117-343434) \nlanguage for the visually handicapped persons",
    "answer": " Louis Braille \n"
}{
    "question": "560)   Braille language is based on _____ convex dots that form all the \nletters and symbols",
    "answer": "  Six \n"
}{
    "question": "561)  The  Indian  Railways  has  renamed  its  security  force  RPF \n(Railway Protection Force)  What is the new name",
    "answer": "  Indian \nRailway Protection Force Service \n"
}{
    "question": "562)  What was the theme of this year's New Delhi World Book Fair",
    "answer": " \n\u2018Gandhi: The Writers\u2019 Writer\u2019 \n"
}{
    "question": "563)  Kota, the coaching capital of India in Rajasthan was in news \nrecently for what reasons",
    "answer": " Over 100 infants died in city\u2019s J K Lon \nHospital \n"
}{
    "question": "564)  Which  institution  hosted  the  Indian  Science  Congress,  the \nbiggest  annual  gathering  of  scientists  in  India  and  abroad",
    "answer": " \nUniversity of Agricultural Sciences, Bengaluru \n"
}{
    "question": "565)  What was the theme of this year's Indian Science Congress",
    "answer": "  \nScience and technology: Rural Development \n"
}{
    "question": "566)  The World Health Organisation (WHO) selected the year 2020 \nas the \u201cYear of the Nurse and Midwife\u201d to commemorate the \nbirthday of which person",
    "answer": "  Florence Nightingale \n"
}{
    "question": "567)  Florence Nightingale was famous nurse, statistician, and social \nreformer from which country",
    "answer": " Britain \n"
}{
    "question": "568)  What was the popular name given to Florence Nightingale",
    "answer": "  \nLady with the lamp \n"
}{
    "question": "569)  India for the first time has been ranked among the top ten in the \nClimate Change Performance Index What is India's rank",
    "answer": " 9th \n"
}{
    "question": "571)  The  Reserve  Bank  launched  mobile  app  \u2018MANI\u2019  for  what \npurpose",
    "answer": "  To  help  the  visually  challenged  identify  the \ndenomination of currency notes \n"
}{
    "question": "573)  Can the MANI app be used for detecting the fake currency",
    "answer": " No \n"
}{
    "question": "574)  As per the Swachh Survekshan League 2020 for assessing the \ncleanliness level of 4,372 cities, which city topped the survey",
    "answer": " \nIndore \n"
}{
    "question": "575)  Which bank has decided to introduce a one-time password for \nevery cash withdrawal of Rs 10,000 and above from its ATMs \nDownload Gyanm App from Play Store  158 \n (Stay Updated on Govt Jobs: WhatsApp 'Hello' to 9117-343434) \nbetween 8 am and 8 pm",
    "answer": " State Bank of India \n"
}{
    "question": "576)  Who are the only two Indians in Wisden\u2019s T20 International \nteam of the decade",
    "answer": " Virat Kohli and JaspritBumrah \n"
}{
    "question": "578)  Name  the  NASA  Astronaut  who  created  a  new  record  for \nthelongest single spaceflight by a woman",
    "answer": " Christina Koch \n"
}{
    "question": "580)  As per recent data, forest and tress cover roughly _____ per cent \nof the total geographic area of the country",
    "answer": " 25 % \n"
}{
    "question": "582)  In terms of forest cover as a percentage of total geographical \narea, with 85o41% area under forest, _________ is at the top",
    "answer": " \nMizoram \n"
}{
    "question": "584)  As Chief of Defence Staff, General Rawat will also head the new \nDepartment of _________",
    "answer": " Military Affairs \n"
}{
    "question": "585)  Which apex organization released the Sustainable Development \nGoals (SDGs) Index for the year 2019-20",
    "answer": " NITI Aayog \n"
}{
    "question": "586)  SDGs Index developed by NITI Aayog is based on 17SDGs \nformulated by which global organization",
    "answer": "UNO-United Nations \nOrganization \n"
}{
    "question": "587)  Which state topped the SDGs index",
    "answer": " Kerala \n"
}{
    "question": "588)  Government has decided to waive the MDR wef Jan1, 2020 on \nall  digital  transactions  using  RuPay  or  UPI  platform  to \npromote digital payments What is full form of MDR",
    "answer": " Merchant \nDiscount Rate  \n"
}{
    "question": "589)  Govt  has  clarified  that  MDR  charge  on  credit  cards \ntransactions will continue to be up to ___________% of the \ntransaction amount",
    "answer": " 2% \n"
}{
    "question": "590)  Which country recently launched the world\u2019s heaviest and most \nadvanced communications satellite, weighing more than eight \ntonnes",
    "answer": " China \n"
}{
    "question": "591)  Name the 32 year old Grandmaster from Andhra, who won the \nWomen\u2019s World Rapid Championship 2019 in Moscow",
    "answer": " Koneru \nDownload Gyanm App from Play Store  159 \n (Stay Updated on Govt Jobs: WhatsApp 'Hello' to 9117-343434) \nHumpy \n"
}{
    "question": "592)  Rohtang Tunnel, one of the longest high altitude tunnels, was in \nnews recently for what reasons",
    "answer": " It has been renamed as Atal \nTunnel \n"
}{
    "question": "593)  The Atal Tunnel passes through which range of Himalayas",
    "answer": " \nPirPanjal \n"
}{
    "question": "594)  The Atal Tunnel connects _______ in Himachal Pradesh with \n_________ in Ladakh",
    "answer": " Manali, Leh \n"
}{
    "question": "595)  Which  country  deployed  recently  its  hypersonic  missile \nAvangard,  capable  of  catching  speeds  up  to  33,000  kmph",
    "answer": " \nRussia \n"
}{
    "question": "596)  Which  railway  station  recently  was  in  news  for  offering  its \npassengers the facility of an Oxygen Parlor",
    "answer": " Nashik \n"
}{
    "question": "597)  As  per  the  statistics  compiled  by  the  US  National  Science \nFoundation,  which  country  contributes  largest  number  of \nscientific articles, accounting for 20o67 per cent of their total \npublications",
    "answer": " China  \n"
}{
    "question": "598)  What  is  India's  rank  in  terms  of  its  contribution  in  the \npublication of scientific articles",
    "answer": " 3rd - 5o31%  \n"
}{
    "question": "599)  What is the full form of FICCI",
    "answer": " Federation of Indian Chambers \nof  Commerce  &  Industry,  Sangita  Reddy, elected  as  the  new \nPresident of the FICCI for 2019-20 \n"
}{
    "question": "600)  Where are the headquarters of FICCI",
    "answer": " New Delhi \n"
}{
    "question": "601)  Which  Indian  district  won  the  UNICEF  2019  Award  for \neffective implementation of Swachh Bharat Mission in water \nsanitation and hygiene sectors",
    "answer": " Kamareddy district of Telangana \n"
}{
    "question": "602)  Niranjan Hiranandani has been elected as the new President of \nwhich apex trade and industry  organization",
    "answer": " Assocham \n"
}{
    "question": "603)  Niranjan Hiranandani is associated with which industry",
    "answer": " Real \nestate  \n"
}{
    "question": "604)  What is the full form of Assocham",
    "answer": "  Associated Chambers of \nCommerce & Industry of India \n"
}{
    "question": "605)  India\u2019s  first  long-distance  CNG  bus  fitted  with  CNG \n(compressed natural gas) cylinders will run from New Delhi to \nwhich other place",
    "answer": " Dehradun  \n"
}{
    "question": "606)  American  Academy  of  Ophthalmology  has  selected  which \nIndian doctor for its \"Life Achievement Honour\"",
    "answer": "  Dr Santosh G \nHonavar \n"
}{
    "question": "607)  Indian Railways has started \u201cHim Darshan Express\u201d, a glass-\nDownload Gyanm App from Play Store  160 \n (Stay Updated on Govt Jobs: WhatsApp 'Hello' to 9117-343434) \nenclosed  vistadome  train  on  which  heritage  route",
    "answer": "  Kalka  - \nShimla route \n"
}{
    "question": "608)   The National Tribal Dance Festival was held in which place in \nChhattisgarh",
    "answer": " Raipur \n"
}{
    "question": "609)  Who was declared as the \u2018Most Famous Teenager in the World\u2019 \nby the United Nations in its 'Decade in Review' report",
    "answer": " Malala \nYousafzai \n"
}{
    "question": "610)  Who has been elected as the new Chief Minister of Jharkhand",
    "answer": " \nHemant Soren \n"
}{
    "question": "611)  The country\u2019s first university for transgender community will be \nopened in Kushinagar district of which state",
    "answer": "  Uttar Pradesh \n"
}{
    "question": "612)  As  per  the  recently  release  \u201cGood  Governance  Index\u201d, \n___________ secure the first position among the Indian states",
    "answer": " \nTamil Nadu  \n"
}{
    "question": "613)  Government launched which scheme aimed at improving the \ngroundwater management in seven states",
    "answer": " Atal Bhujal Yojana \n"
}